Jiang Li.
Jiang Li,
your letter is approved.
See where Mr. Shen has assigned you.
This time,
the Court of State Ceremonial
categorized the reception.
Liu Xu, Shijie, and I are
with the Ministry of Rites,
responsible for reception
along the way and the lodge.
"Music Affairs Division"?
Music Affairs Division?
This isn't right.
You play the guqin so well.
Yet they make you play ordinary pieces
with those musicians.
What's going on here?
Which part does Mr. Shen oversee?
Of course Mr. Shen oversees everything.
He and those
at the Hanlin Academy are responsible
for compiling and organizing classics
for Great Zhao.
This is the main focus
of the alliance meeting.
Shen Yurong.
You're so afraid that I'm so close to you.
Are you afraid
I'll find something incriminating
or that Wanning will go crazy
because of you
and do something incriminating?
It seems like you will be the first
to slip up.
- Yes.
- Of course.
Seriously?
BROADEN KNOWLEDGE WITH PROPRIETY
Yes, we must finish this.
Isn't she the Annual Exam top scorer
at the School of Integrity?
What is she doing
at the Music Affairs Division?
Shouldn't she be doing a solo?
Ms. Jiang Li,
you cannot touch this guqin.
It belongs to Ms. Xiao.
Where's mine?
You're just like them, it's over there.
I want to see Ms. Xiao.
Who's looking for me?
Ms. Xiao.
I heard from Mr. Shen before
that His Majesty wants
to hear me play solo.
But I'm assigned to you.
With this arrangement,
isn't His Majesty's wish being ignored?
Ms. Jiang Li,
I know you won first place
in the Annual Exam
and gained His Majesty's admiration,
so you are proud and confident.
But look at these musicians
from the Music Office.
They're all proud and confident too.
If you don't show some real skill,
you won't be able to convince them.
Mr. Shen knows
your guqin skills are top-notch.
That's why he wanted you to come
and set an example for them.
Ms. Jiang Li,
could it be that you can't put aside
your noble status?
We can't afford
to have a sham among the skilled
in receiving the Great Zhao delegation.
But Ms. Jiang Li has a special status,
so she'll be excused this time.
Today, I need everyone here to bear
with Ms. Jiang Li until she catches up.
These are the pieces you usually play.
I just received the sheet music recently,
so catching up
to everyone's level is challenging indeed.
But I don't want to drag everyone down
because I'm a Chancellor's daughter.
Ms. Xiao,
I'm willing to practice alone
to catch up to everyone's level.
In that case, do as you wish.
You may practice alone.
Ms. Jiang Li,
you need to practice diligently.
If you fall behind,
I can't afford
to have Mr. Shen blame me.
Ms. Xiao, don't worry.
I won't let you down.
Great.
Help!
I… I've been bitten.
What happened?
I found Jiuyue.
Where is Jiuyue?
I wanted to go to the snake cave
to catch snakes.
He insisted on following me
and couldn't stop nagging.
He ended up getting bitten by a snake.
How dare you hit me?
Where's the antidote?
Trade your ten-year-old fine wine for it.
Fine.
Wen Ji said
you were looking for me urgently.
Your brother is leading
the Great Zhao delegation
and coming here
for an alliance meeting soon.
You'll be reunited with him then.
That's great news.
Prince Cheng doesn't want us
to be friendly with Great Zhao.
He'll definitely stop it from happening,
which could endanger you.
During this time,
stay at the Duke Mansion.
You'll be safer here.
Is that why you asked me to come?
Are you that concerned about me?
There's one more thing.
What is it?
Save two people.
One has amnesia
and the other is disfigured by a knife.
Xiao Heng.
Do you see everyone
as pawns?
After it's done,
you can have all the wine you want.
Wine?
That's two lives we're talking about.
How can that be enough?
What do you propose then?
Tell me.
For whose sake
do you want to save those two?
You're struggling to answer.
Is it for Ms. Jiang Li again?
Will you save them or not?
Is this how you ask for help?
What do you want me to do?
I want you
to accompany me to catch spiders.
Show me your sincerity.
I thought you wanted to catch spiders.
- Are we catching them here?
- Yes.
I'm not here to swim with you.
To catch water spiders,
we have to catch them from the water.
Wait here.
Keep an eye on her.
Yes.
Why are you back?
While undressing, she was saying
that if I stay,
she'll tell Great Zhao's emperor
that she was molested.
Xiao Heng!
It turns out you truly care about me.
If you don't want to save them,
you don't have to toy with me like this.
I…
Xiao Heng,
haven't you toyed with me before?
The arrow is poisoned.
Only I can cure it.
If you want me to save you,
you have to offer yourself to me.
I don't do romance.
It's up to you to save me or not.
Is your refusal to indulge in romance
only meant for me?
So you're not going
to save those two people then.
I can save them
as long as you offer your life in return.
Jiuyue, stop messing around.
Fine,
I'll stop.
As for those two,
I can save them or not.
Jiuyue.
Lu Ji,
keep her safe.
Yes.
HANLIN ACADEMY
Mr. Shen,
this is the budget for meals
from the Court of State Ceremonial.
Please review it.
BANQUET EXPENSES OVERVIEW
Mr. Shen, this is the repertoire
of the Music Affairs Division.
Please review this too.
Thank you.
The alliance meeting with Great Zhao
is of great significance.
I'll need more help from both of you.
Please inform me promptly of any issues.
Yes.
Ms. Xiao, do you have something to say?
It's nothing urgent.
It's just that Ms. Jiang Li
has been absent from rehearsals
for two days.
She said she was not well
and might need more days of rest.
Resting is understandable.
But she's unfamiliar
with the new repertoire.
If we wait for her to recover,
she might hold back
the Music Affairs Division's performance.
If her health can't handle it,
it's better for her to get proper rest.
Shijie, why are you here?
Xiao Deyin said you're not well,
so I brought medicine for you.
Thank you, Shijie.
But how did you get sick
just from practicing the guqin?
Shijie,
I remember you mentioned before
that His Majesty wanted to hear me play
"Spring Fading into White Pear Blossoms."
That's correct.
But why did Mr. Shen place me
in the Music Affairs Division?
He said he hoped you'd inspire
the Music Affairs Division to work harder.
But following Mr. Shen's instructions,
Ms. Xiao gave me new sheet music.
Instead of highlighting my strengths,
it exposed my weaknesses.
It's my fault for being too busy lately
that I overlooked you.
I'll go and see Mr. Shen shortly.
I really don't want to stay
in the Music Affairs Division.
If you do want to help me,
I have a solution.
HONGXIAO GRAND CEREMONY
Your thorough arrangement puts my mind
at ease, Minister Shen.
There's something
I shouldn't trouble Your Majesty with.
But it concerns Jiang Li,
the Chief Secretariat's daughter,
so I dare not make decisions on my own.
Go on.
Your Majesty wants Ms. Jiang Li
to represent Great Yan
and showcase her guqin skills.
But the alliance meeting
isn't like the Annual Exam.
Her performance in the latter
would only affect herself.
It has been several months
since the Annual exam,
and many things happened after that,
making her guqin skills unavoidably rusty.
I initially thought of letting her
practice at the Music Affairs Division.
But she fell ill unexpectedly.
Forcing her
might not only be detrimental
to the alliance meeting,
but also make the Chief Secretariat feel
that my arrangements aren't good.
Minister Shen, what do you suggest then?
Let Ms. Jiang Li focus on recovering.
Your Majesty, Mr. Shen.
Upon hearing that my cousin was sick,
I went to visit her.
Ms. Xiao gave Jiang Li a music piece
that the musicians know well,
but was unfamiliar to her.
Jiang Li practiced day and night
to not burden the Music Affairs Division
and fell ill.
She continued practicing in spite of that,
showing her dedication.
The alliance meeting is important.
Given Jiang Li's current condition,
even if she doesn't practice new pieces
and only plays
"Spring Fading into White Pear Blossoms",
she might not be as good as she was
at the Annual Exam even if she recovers.
Your Majesty, please consider this.
Jiang Li just needs a few days of rest
to recover from her illness.
She may not be
as good as she was in the Annual Exam,
but Jiang Li is talented and devoted.
If we don't stick
to the Annual Exam repertoire,
perhaps she could recite poems
and play the guqin with Hanlin scholars
to create a new performance style,
highlighting each other's strengths
and covering weaknesses,
which could be refreshing
to the Zhao delegation.
How is that appropriate?
Minister Shen, calm down.
Minister Ye's proposal is intriguing.
Innovating has always been your forte.
Minister Shen,
you might as well give it a try.
- Yes.
Your pawn
always involves me
like this unnecessarily.
That's her talent.
So tell me,
what does she ultimately want to do?
Perhaps Your Majesty should ask
Ms. Jiang Li?
I guess there are still things
that even you can't figure out.
Interesting.
HANLIN ACADEMY
Isn't this Ms. Jiang Li?
Are you here at the Hanlin Academy
to catch the eye
of some young master again?
I've told you before.
If you miss out on me,
you won't find anyone better.
Your outfit today looks nice.
Did you have a blind date
with someone inside?
I… I'm here at the Hanlin Academy
to participate in compiling the classics.
As for you,
what are you doing here?
Mr. Shen summoned me.
Mr. Shen?
You two just made a scene
in front of His Majesty
and you still dare to interact?
Aren't you afraid of gossip?
A clear conscience fears no slander.
Impressive.
Why did you ask me to come, Mr. Shen?
Didn't your cousin tell you?
Since you're in charge of this matter,
it only counts if it comes from you.
His Majesty
has approved Ye Shijie's proposal.
Who would you like to perform with
at the Hanlin Academy?
Naturally, you…
have the final say.
In that case,
do it with Zhao Qi.
You seemed quite close just now.
It saves time in getting acquainted.
Can you choose someone else?
Didn't you say I have the final say?
Since you insist,
I'll follow your arrangement.
I'll go talk to Zhao Qi
and start rehearsals tomorrow.
Baixue,
I remember my cousin, Jia'er,
gave me some silk and satin before.
There was a handwoven
cloud brocade handkerchief.
Bring it to me later.
My lady, you should have used it earlier.
Such good material
should match a beautiful woman like you.
It's not for my personal use.
Then what is it for?
To please others.
I was actually looking forward
to your performance.
Now,
I've become a part of this show.
I know you don't want to perform with me.
Neither do I.
So go talk to Mr. Shen and decline it.
Me?
- Yes.
- Forget it.
If I offend Mr. Shen,
can I still stay at Hanlin Academy?
Besides,
this is also an opportunity
to impress His Majesty.
Why would I decline it?
You must go.
Otherwise, your parents will find out
about the lady you're keeping--
- Are you going or not?
- Is that a threat?
I'm not just threatening you.
There's also a bribe.
I heard you've been searching
for this cloud brocade handkerchief.
Today, I brought you a top-notch one.
Take a look.
Will it catch the eye of your sweetheart?
Let me take a look.
This cloud brocade handkerchief
is from Luyang.
It's hard to find in the capital.
How…
How did you get it?
My maternal grandmother's family
is from Luyang.
Then
I'll reluctantly cooperate
with you.
Please replace me with someone else
for Ms. Jiang Li.
We discussed marriage before.
If we perform together,
it'll inevitably draw criticism.
If you have a clear conscience,
why care about what others think?
Even though I have a clear conscience,
gossip is a fearful thing.
It's a tribute to Great Zhao.
I hope you can set aside personal emotions
and prioritize the bigger picture.
Mr. Shen.
Mr. Shen--
We don't have much time left.
Let's go inside and rehearse.
HANLIN ACADEMY
Yurong,
they're not even rehearsing.
What are they doing inside?
I tried to persuade him to replace me.
But he wouldn't listen.
Put on another act for me.
What? Again?
Does your sweetheart
like that handkerchief?
I have even better ones.
I'll bring them tomorrow.
You can let her choose.
Just this once, I won't do it again.
All right.
Go home.
Jiang Li,
are you doing this on purpose?
All along,
you must have planned this.
I planned this?
What scheme could I have?
It was Mr. Shen who asked me to come.
How would I know he wanted me
to work with you?
You don't know?
Stop pretending already.
I made it clear to you before.
We're not suitable.
Now, you're throwing yourself at me,
people might think
we're getting back together.
How can I get married in the future?
Do you think
you're the only one who minds?
There's nothing we can do now.
I don't have anything to say to you.
That makes the two of us.
Mr. Shen, I apologize for that.
Go home first.
Yurong.
I said, go.
Ms. Jiang Li,
what happened here?
Weren't you two rehearsing
just fine earlier?
- Did you do this on purpose, Mr. Shen?
- I did this on purpose?
I overheard the conversation
between you and Zhao Qi this afternoon.
It seemed like
you deliberately brought someone
who discussed marriage with me
to stir up trouble and make me pull out.
Ms. Jiang Li, you're mistaken.
Zhao Qi is a highly talented man
among the Hanlin scholars.
If I didn't do this,
I would have let down
your deliberate suggestion
to have Minister Ye propose ideas
in front of His Majesty.
Mr. Shen, mind your words.
You were the one who tried to get rid
of me in front of His Majesty first.
You were absent due to illness first.
I don't know
how I ever offended you, Mr. Shen.
You've been suspicious of me
and targeting me all along.
Helping with the alliance meeting
would bring honor to Great Yan
and add glory to the Jiang family.
So I won't give up.
If you continue
making things difficult for me,
it will reflect poorly on Great Yan.
Tomorrow,
I'll find another person for you.
Mr. Zhao.
Mr. Du.
- Can we talk?
- What's the matter?
Mr. Shen assigned me to rehearse a program
with Ms. Jiang Li.
Congratulations, Mr. Du.
When you shine brightly
in the alliance meeting
and please His Majesty,
it will be beneficial for your career.
It looks good on the surface.
However, why did you
decline it with Mr. Shen?
I'm telling you this
because you're my friend.
What seems good on the surface
often hides underlying tensions.
How so?
Let me put it this way.
Jiang Li is really evil.
She really eats people.
What? She really eats people?
It was just a metaphor.
I just want to let you know
that sometimes
something appears to be a blessing,
but it's actually
a bottomless abyss underneath.
What should I do then?
Jiang Li is coming to rehearse
with me tonight.
Mr. Zhao,
could you give me some advice?
Mr. Shen is kind.
He understood my difficulty
and changed his decision.
If you have difficulties too,
there's bound to be someone
with no difficulties
among so many scholars in Hanlin.
I understand it now.
Thank you, Mr. Zhao.
Go
and ask Jiang Li
for the pearl necklace she promised.
Yes.
RESPECT THE TRUTH
- Mr. Cheng, please come this way.
- All right.
- Leave these here.
- Then I'll go and see them tomorrow.
- I'll get going.
- I'll go with you.
- All right.
- Liu, take care.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
I craved cold drinks last night
and mixed ice cubes in water.
Now, my stomach hurts terribly.
Come on, I'll take you to the physician.
No.
I couldn't hold it earlier.
I've already…
soiled my trousers.
You…
Mr. Shen,
I'll go home first to wash up
and change my clothes.
Then I'll see a physician.
I might not be able
to attend tonight's rehearsal.
I hope you can keep this a secret
and protect my reputation.
I'll take my leave now.
HANLIN ACADEMY
Ms. Jiang Li,
why do you…
My carriage broke down on the way.
I had to walk over, so I'm late.
I can begin now.
I found Mr. Du, a talented scholar
among the Hanli students,
to perform with you.
Unfortunately,
- he--
- It's fine.
I know no one wants to perform with me.
I'm all soaked, but end up with nothing.
Mr. Shen, I must look foolish.
Jiang Li,
everything I said earlier was true.
I had no intention
of playing tricks on you.
He really isn't feeling well today.
I'm not blaming you.
I'm blaming myself.
For so many years,
I've carried the stigma
of matricide and fratricide.
The Eldest Princess
questioned my identity,
my mother went mad,
and my father is away from home.
It's no wonder you avoided me before this.
At this alliance meeting,
I just wanted to make a name for myself.
I didn't expect
that all of you
already see me as a jinx.
Take shelter here first.
Leave when the rain stops.
Put this on for now.
You can leave when the rain lets up.
This is Garden of Eloquence
by Liu Xiang from the Han Dynasty.
Exactly.
Dear, you should include
Garden of Eloquence in the compilation.
My father mentioned
he was very interested
in Garden of Eloquence.
But most of it has been lost now.
He said if someone could collect
and recompile it,
it would be a great merit.
GARDEN OF ELOQUENCE
I remember it has 20 volumes,
but most of them are lost.
I didn't expect you to collect so much.
It took me quite an effort
to gather these fragments.
That's why I plan
to compile them into a book.
This way, this classic
can be passed down through generations
and benefit future generations.
Mr. Shen, you're really amazing.
Ms. Jiang Li, you're too kind.
But you
were able to recognize Garden of Eloquence
with just these fragments.
That's quite surprising.
Mr. Shen, you're different
from what I imagined.
How so?
I thought
those favored by His Majesty
would be skilled in social interactions.
I didn't expect you
to rely on your knowledge.
You truly have remarkable qualities.
I'm just following the principles
in the book.
An official should follow
the six righteous paths.
Being humble and diligent,
progressing daily in virtue,
recommending the virtuous and talented
tirelessly and upholding the law.
The book says there are six righteous
and six unrighteous paths.
Following righteous paths brings honor,
while the other disgrace.
A virtuous official follows
the righteous paths and avoids the other,
thus ensuring stability
and good governance.
Mr. Shen,
if a person acts righteously
but also commits unrighteous acts,
is this person still righteous or not?
All things follow the laws
of heaven and earth.
If one goes against their conscience,
no matter how many good deeds they do,
they will face divine retribution.
I believe
you're a person who acts uprightly.
Ms. Jiang Li, the rain has stopped.
I'll take my leave.
Thank you
for not minding talking with me.
I'll take my leave now.
I'll return your clothes
after washing them.
HANLIN ACADEMY
What gross encounter did you have
to torture yourself like this?
Duke Su,
why are you here?
Your clothes
look terrible.
Come with me.
HANLIN ACADEMY
Does it fit?
Why don't you have women's clothes
at your place?
You already know my background.
Don't you know why?
They say you don't like women.
But why?
Women are wonderful.
They're caring
and considerate.
What about you?
You're not getting any younger.
You're the one who's getting older.
I actually feel quite good
living alone these days.
No emotions to worry about
and free to act.
You're the one
who truly fits that description.
Thanks for the compliment.
But there's something
I need to remind you of.
Getting close to Shen Yurong
is a risky move.
I have to do it.
I want to face him
just like he faced Xue Fangfei
in her grave.
I need to find his weakness
to clear Xue Fangfei's name.
What weakness?
I haven't found it yet.
Over time, he will eventually slip up.
Have you considered the consequences?
Xiao Heng,
you can be more frank.
Eldest Princess' retaliation
could cost me my life.
And my all-or-nothing gamble
might also be a path
to my own destruction.
Admitting it
means you're afraid.
Having fear is a good thing.
I actually feel quite relieved
after saying it out loud to you.
Do I also have a therapeutic effect?
Anyway, I have nothing to lose.
Have some chicken.
Has Jiuyue returned?
She was here. But she left.
Don't worry about Magistrate Xue
and that young lady.
I remember them.
But you know what she's like.
She is too willful.
I'm sorry to trouble you.
You have to promise me one thing.
No matter what plans
you make in the future,
don't get yourself caught up in them.
You have nothing to lose.
But it may not be the same for me.
All right.
It's burned.
Yurong, where were you?
At the Hanlin Academy.
Compiling the classics
has been very hectic these days.
Stop pretending.
Your sister told me everything
when she got back.
Tonight,
were you with Jiang Li?
No.
You still don't understand
the seriousness of this matter.
Have you forgotten
the suffering our family went through?
Father,
I will avenge you.
After taking revenge
on this corrupt official,
there will be others who would oppress us.
Unless you become an official,
not only will you fail to take revenge,
but you'll also bring trouble
to our family.
Don't worry.
I will study hard
and become a top scorer.
Then I'll be a good official
and eradicate all corrupt ones
who mistreat the people!
Have you forgotten
your promise to your father
on his deathbed?
How difficult was it
to get to where you are now?
What do you think
Her Highness would feel if she found out
you were associating with Ms. Jiang Li,
who looks like Xue Fangfei?
They are not the same person.
Mother, stop mixing them up.
Is that the point?
Does my opinion matter?
The point is Her Highness believes
she's Xue Fangfei.
Think about your grand ambitions.
Think about how our family
got our good life now.
Yurong,
do not play with fire.
Mother, you don't need to remind me.
I know the path
I must take better than anyone.
My lord,
you won't believe it.
Being poisoned
felt quite fascinating.
I saw so many beautiful women around me.
I just hugged them all.
Then I…
Then let Jiuyue catch another snake
to bite you again.
Don't.
I was just joking.
Is she drunk?
How much did she drink?
It's wine with a venomous scorpion.
Too strong.
Perfect.
Keep her confined at the mansion
until the Zhao delegation arrives.
Wen Ji,
take her to her room.
Lu Ji,
come with me to the liquor shop.
- Yes.
- Isn't Lu Ji holding her?
Let Lu Ji take her inside.
Now that you're no longer poisoned,
you can continue watching over her.
I…
You…
Don't.
Let me out!
Guards!
Somebody!
Am I not a person?
Stay there.
Before the Zhao delegation arrives,
you're not going anywhere.
How dare you?
I have never been locked up
since I was a child.
You'd better let me go now.
Or else…
Or else what?
Wen Ji,
what do you want?
I've already prepared myself.
Don't think you can poison me again.
Anyway,
you're not stepping out
of the Duke Mansion today.
Wen Ji, how dare you?
Just stay put.
Don't think about leaving.
I need to go to Ye Residence.
Didn't Xiao Heng ask me
to treat Magistrate Xue?
I'm going to treat him. I want to go now.
Do you think I'll fall for that?
You'd better get this straight.
Xiao Heng even went spider hunting with me
to make me treat Magistrate Xue.
And you should know
what Jiang Li means to him, right?
If Magistrate Xue isn't treated in time,
it'll be all your fault.
Then
you won't just get caned
a few times anymore.
You are…
I'm here to treat Magistrate Xue.
You can't come in.
This is trespassing.
I can report you to the authorities.
Vice Director Ye,
we're here on Duke Su's orders
to treat Magistrate Xue.
Ms. Jiang Li also knows about this.
Do you work for Duke Su?
You know him, right?
Can I go in now?
No.
Jiang Li didn't tell me about this.
Let me inform her first.
You don't need to bother with this.
I get it now.
He doesn't like Xiao Heng, right?
Watch your words.
Can you be more subtle?
His lordship
just doesn't want to stoop to his level.
Guys,
please watch your words.
Stop beating around the bush.
- Are you letting me in or not?
- No.
No?
Ye Shijie, don't provoke her.
She will--
Keep an eye on him.
I'm going in to do the treatment.
Stop right there!
It's wise to listen.
You…
Don't touch him!
You're welcome.
His illness
is tricky to cure.
Wait.
Where did this quack come from?
Who gave you the permission
to touch Magistrate Xue?
Where am I?
I'm the only one
who can treat his illness.
But it can't be cured in one day.
If the poison--
If the treatment is too strong,
it could be fatal.
So I will come once a day from now on.
If you have any questions,
you can just ask Jiang Li.
Wen Ji,
take him outside.
The next treatment is highly toxic,
so you'd better stay away.
I'm not leaving.
Do you think
you don't look pathetic enough?
Give me the antidote!
I can walk myself out!
Can you give me the antidote first?
What's the rush?
She'll give it to you when she's done.
Wen Ji!
Give me the antidote!
Find Xiao Heng.
Catch it.
Don't just stand there! Find his lordship!
The antidote.
Open your mouth!
His lordship is at the wine shop.
Just surrender now.
You're no match for me.
Do you think you can last
until Xiao Heng gets here?
Him?
He's no match for me…
We can only take our chances.
What are you planning to do?
That seems to be effective.
But why do I feel
that I'm also…